他们有蜂蜜果仁甜麦圈?
They got Honey Nut Cheerios in here?
靠
Shit.
喂 滚远点 狗娘养的
Yo, back the fuck up, motherfucker!
我兄弟给我留的位子
My man here saved my spot, yo.
真可惜咱没多少时间相处
It's a shame we don't have more time together.
不然能生几个娃了
We could have made us a couple of babies.
大家啥都没看到哇
Ain't nobody see shit.
- 这信息传得怎么样? - 不赖
- How's that for a message? - Not bad.
问题是这下悬赏要你头的钱 不是四位数是五位数了
Except the price on your head ain't for four figures it's for five.
靠 那么值钱 不如我自己干掉你算了
Shit. For that kind of money, I should have done you my own self.
谁在领钱干活?
So who's doing the bounty?
一个西边来的玩家 叫Marlo
Who it is: A West Side player by the name of Marlo.
Marlo 好像还真没听说过
Marlo? Can't say I know the man.
他可认识你
He know you.
能让我打个电话不
Can you get me a phone call?
比这更好的都行
I can do you one better than that.
你打给谁?
Who you calling?
- 警察 - 警察?
- Police. - The police?
那家伙欠我个人情
Man owe me a favor.
火线重案组 第四季 第7集
the.wire.s04e07
* When you walk through the garden *
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* you gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* keep the devil *
嗯 这可是金科玉律 - The Bunk
犯罪 爆率 毒品
...crime, violence, drugs,
毒瘾 失败的学校
drug addiction, failing schools--
这些巴尔的摩的社会问题
all of these social problems in Baltimore City
一再地出现
over and over again.
6月8号 我在写一篇第二天的专栏
And on June 8th, when I had to write a column for the next day,
刚巧看到FBI最新发布的数据
some statistics had just come out from the FBl showing
提到巴尔的摩的犯罪率上升问题
an uptick in some of Baltimore's crime.
居然还接连发生了五起杀人案
And we also had a spate of five killings
也就是两三天里的事儿
in a two- or three-day period.
于是 想到要坐下来
And, you know, the idea of sitting down again
再写一篇关于这个话题的专栏--
and writing another column on this subject--
我不知道是否重要
I don't know if it is important.
但我是巴蒂尔摩的一名市民
But here I am a citizen of Baltimore,
我把市民身份和专栏作家的身份 看得一样重要
and I take my citizenship as seriously as I take my credentials as a columnist.
我说 我要说什么呢 能说些什么呢
I said, "What am I gonna say? What can I say about this?"
如果杀戮还将继续--
If the killings continue--
一年250到300起凶杀案...
between 250 and 300 homicides a year...
- 一步登天 - 一步登天
- Top of the world. - Top of the world.
我推翻了现任市长 Tony  这可不是简单的事啊
I knocked off an incumbent major, Tony. That ain't easy.
党组织不能够忘了你
National party has to take note of this.
像你这样年轻又帅气 他们自有安排
Young and pretty as you are, I'm sure they've got ideas.
你只管好好管理这城市
All you have to do now is run the city.
Tony 问你个事儿
Tony, I've got to ask you something:
你首次任期满了为啥不竞选连任 你看...
Why didn't you run again after the first term? I mean...
你的那些关系和组织 谁都没有
nobody had the-- the name you had, the organization.
我给你讲个故事吧 Tommy
Let me tell you a story, Tommy.
我当上市长的第一天 他们让我在桌前坐下
The first day I became mayor, they sit me down at the desk--
大椅子 红木桌子
big chair and dark wood,
好多漂亮玩意儿
lots of beautiful things.
我就想啦 还能往哪儿好了去哇
I'm thinking, "How much better can it get?"
结果房间一角有人敲门
There's a knock at the door in the corner of the room,
Pete走了进来
and Pete comes walking in
端着个华丽无比的
carrying this gorgeous
纯银做的碗 手工錾刻
Sres silver bowl, hand chased.
有这么大
It was this big.
"是工会送来的"他说
"It's from the unions," he says.
我还以为是个礼物呢
So I think it's a present,
祝贺我第一天坐上市长交椅
something to commemorate my first day as mayor.
结果他走过来 往桌上一放
And he walks over, puts it on a desk.
我低头一看
I look down at it.
恶心死人
It's disgusting.
我说 "这啥玩意儿啊?"
I said, "What the hell is this?"
他说 "你觉得它看起来像啥?"
He said, "What the hell's it look like?"
我说 "看起来像屎一样"
I said, "lt looks like shit.
"你让我拿它干嘛?"
"Well, what do you want me to do with it?"
他说 "吃了它"
He says, "Eat it."
"吃了它?"
"Eat it?"
他说 "对哇"
He says, "Yeah.
"您是市长"
"You're the mayor.
"你不吃谁吃"
"You've got to eat it."
好嘛 咱这不是第一天上任么
So, okay. It was my first day,
Pete好歹比我有经验
and Pete knows more than I do.
我就硬着头皮吃了呗
So I go at it.
我刚吃完 敲门声又响了
And just when I finish, there's a knock on the door.
Pete又捧着个银碗走了进来
And in walks Pete carrying another silver bowl,
这次是黑人的 "又吃?"
and this one's from the blacks. "This too?"
他点点头 我只能开吃
And he nods. I start eating.
等我吃完 又敲门又来一个碗
And when I'm finished, there's another knock and another bowl.
这次是波兰佬的
This one's from the Polacks.
那之后又来个教会的
Then after that, one from the ministers.
你知道吗 Tommy
And you know what, Tommy?
就这么回事儿
That's what it is.
整天就是坐在那里 不停地吃屎
You're sitting, eating shit all day long,
一天又一天 一年又一年
day after day, year after year.
等我意识到以后
When I realized that,
我决定还是做个商业律师吧
I decided being a downtown lawyer
还能每晚见见家人
and seeing my family every night
享享天伦之乐
made for a fine life.
天伦之乐啊
Just a fine life.
啥事儿让这黑鬼忙得屁颠殿的啊
Man, everyone knows his nigga ain't about to cop, is he?
Spider Spider 别走哇
Spider, Spider, hold on now.
等等啊
Come on, man.
你怎么不来我的健身房了?
Why you ain't come past my gym no more?
我等了你几个礼拜了
I been waiting on you for weeks now.
你倒是说话呀 孩子
Talk to me, son.
你他妈又不是我爹
You ain't my fuckin' father.
我跟你妈之间的事儿
What happened between me and your mom
和你来用健身房没关系
ain't got shit to do with you taking advantage of the gym.
年轻人 我只觉得你个好小子
Now, man, I'm just saying you one of my best, boy.
要是我知道这会让你伤心 我也不会--
Hell, if I thought it was gonna hurt you, I wouldn't--
放屁 谁也不能让我伤心
Fuck you! Ain't nobody gonna hurt me.
去死吧 赶紧走滚远点 爷叔
Fuck you. So step up and step off, unc.
有客户能证明我说的
I got customers backing up.
黑马哟 黑马喂
Dark horse, dark horse.
跟五个 再加五个
Five, and five more.
靠 会这样啊
Shit. That's what that does.
Withers校长 请至食堂
Principal Withers, please to the cafeteria.
喂 最后张牌朝下 忘了?
Yo, last card down. Remember?
哦 对 我错了
Oh yeah. My bad.
喂 我说
Hey, guys.
我同意你们平时上这儿来吃午饭
You know I don't mind you coming up here most days to eat lunch,
可我说了不允许赌博
but I said you can't be gambling.
Prezbo老师
Yo, Mr. Prezbo,
这两毛五分是个 呃 提醒
the quarter's only a, you know, reminder
提醒我有25个开心果 仅此而已
to remind me that I got 25 shells. That's all.
来吧 看看你有什么牌
Come on, let's see what you've got.
靠 同花顺
Dang. Flush.
- 可这打不过你三个九吧 - 打过呀
- But it don't beat your three nines. - Yeah, it do.
- 打过? - 打过
- It do? - It do.
是打"得"过
It does.
Karim 你下注该小心些 算算概率
Karim, you should have been more cautious with your bet. Figure the odds.
靠 午间休息 别又来教训我们
Yo, it's our lunch break. Don't be schooling us now.
等等 让他说
Hold on. Let him talk.
首先 你得算算有多少方块
Well, for starters, you have to get a count on the diamonds.
你们知道一副牌有多少方块么
You know how many diamonds there are in a deck?
13 对了 玩牌就是数字游戏
13-- that's right. Cards is all about knowing the numbers.
记住数字 你就能算概率了
With the numbers, you can calculate the odds.
你看 Michael拿出来四张方块儿
Now, Michael had four diamonds showing.
等等 那色子呢?
Hold on. Wait. What about dice?
色子也有概率么
I mean, does dice have odds too?
我们一般都玩色子的
'Cause mostly that's what we play.
色子? 当然有啦
Dice? Yeah. Sure.
你能教教我们色子的概率不?
So, can you show us the odds of dice?
- 对哇 - 对 教我们色子吧
- Yeah, man. - Yeah, man. Teach us dice.
- 那可就爽了 伙计 - 真的
- That'd be hard, man. - For real.
然后是那个坐牢鬼Rick
Here comes that Jailhouse Rick.
Bradock那案子?
The Braddock case?
我以为现在我们不是能够结案了么
I take it we now have permission to solve this fucking case,
反正大家都投票完了
seeing as everyone's finished voting.
那就结呗 你们这些勇猛的百夫长
Solve away, you bold centurions.
你没事儿干?
You don't have work to do?
电话来前没事儿
Not till I catch a fresh call, no.
这个能卖多少钱?
How much can you sell that one for?
全新出售的话 300
Mint condition, 300.
我靠 我也得培养个爱好了
Fuck me. I need a hobby.
没错 可是他顶撞的我
That's right, but he bucked on me.
我想他总会回来一两次吧
I just thought he might have come back past once or twice.
Sherrod在缺席名单上 Cousins先生
Sherrod's on a truant list, Mr. Cousins.
自从上次你带他来他就没出现过
He hasn't been back since the last time you brought him in.
那 他要真回来了  您能不能告诉他我在家等他
Well, if he does come back past, can you tell him I'm looking for him at home,
告诉他想回来就能回来?
and he can come home if he want?
抱歉耽搁您时间了
I apologize for taking your time.
你是来卧底的吧
I see you up here undercover.
好啦 别慌小子 我不会说的
All right. Don't worry, dawg. I'll keep it close.
Donnelly太太?
Mrs. Donnelly?
学校有没有什么棋牌游戏--
Does the school have any kind of collection of board games--
双骰戏 烦棋 大富翁?
Parcheesi, Trouble, Monopoly?
你不是教八年级数学的么?
You're still teaching eighth-grade math, right?
这不想办法么
Trying. Yeah.
楼下藏书室
The book room downstairs.
别偏了大纲 Pryzbylewski老师
Stay on the curriculum, Mr. Pryzbylewski,
免得招来个地区学督来盯着我们
or you'll have an area superintendent on our backs.
记得这个么?
Remember this, yo?
这不是我的案子
Not in my case.
管案子的那帮小子不听我说啊
Them boys working the case ain't really in the mood to listen.
你看我跟这美女律师可是有约在先的
As you can see, I still got the lady-lawyer marker,
别忘了 不久前有把警枪还开过火呢
and if I recall, a police gun got fired a while back.
我来这儿就是为了那枪的事儿
Only reason I'm even here is because of that gun.
至于Ilene Nathan那边
As far as llene Nathan goes,
她是承诺过一两桩案子能给你免罪金牌
she promised a get-out-of-jail-free on a small felony or two.
这可是有目击证人的纳税人遭谋杀案
This here is a taxpayer murder with an eyeball witness.
目击证人说谎啊 搞什么
The eyeball witness is lying, yo. Come on now.
你知道的 我怎么会朝不是帮派的人开枪?
When have you ever known me to put my gun on anybody that wasn't in the gang?
哦 Omar
Oh. Omar.
老脸皮Andre诬赖我
Old Face Andre is lying on me here.
那个开店的 他干嘛要说谎?
The store owner-- now why would he lie?
- Andre的店还有别的生意 - 哈
- Andre working a package out the store. - Ah.
像那种人 多少都会恨咱这种人
Folk like that, they tend to bear a certain resentment toward folk like me.
就算这次不是你 那别的怎么说--
If you didn't do this, when you did others--
妈的 我还有去年两件双重谋杀没结呢
shit, I got files on two open doubles last year.
两起现场都有猎枪弹壳
Shotgun shells at both scenes.
藏毒窝点的枪战又怎么说?
What about that stash-house gunfight?
啊?
Hmm?
Stringer Bell和保镖命丧仓库怎么说?
What about Stringer Bell and his muscle dead in the warehouse?
就算这次你不栽 也要栽在其他十几件案子上
If this one ain't on you, another dozen probably are.
如果这件案子上了法庭 你好歹还有个申辩的机会
And if this one goes to court, you can tell that jury how wrong it is.
可是在站到宣誓台前我可是孤立无援啊
Obviously, a guy's alone before I swear to them on the stand.
你让我出庭 我必死无疑
You leave me at courtside and I'm done.
- 你懂的 - 哦?
- You know that. - Yeah?
你梁子结了不少
So you ain't making friends.
有个赏金猎人想要我的头 五位数
I got a bounty on my head, man-- five figures.
早知道我什么都和这帮兄弟分了
If I would have known I'd be sharing quarters with all these boys,
也不会剥削他们剥削得这么惨
I probably wouldn't have robbed so many of them.
是哇 那可是金科玉律
Aw yeah, that golden rule.
你觉得自己背负神圣使命充满正义什么的 可你好好想想
Well, since you feeling all Biblical and righteous and all, you think on this:
那个送货的女人要不是Omar杀的 杀人凶手就另有其人
Now if Omar ain't killed that delivery lady, somebody else did.
你这样可就让他逍遥法外了不是?
But you giving him a free walk right now, though, ain't you?
做人要讲原则
A man got to have a code.
怎么了?
What's up?
就拿色子
Just the dice.
有色子的都拿出来
Grab the dice from any game that has them.
我们上的是第三版 是吧?
We're using that third edition, right?
我不知道
I don't know.
是第三版 那这些第五版的扔在箱子里 算怎么回事?
We're using the third. What are the new fifth editions doing sitting down here in a box?
不会吧
No way.
大红袍卖了哈
Big red, y'all.
大红袍便宜卖了
Big reds over here.
- 你好啊 伙计 - 卖大黄了哇
- What's up, man? - Got your big yellow.
今天怎样啊
What's up?
大黄这儿买哈
Big yellow for you.
你看你一脸生意人样
Look at you, all business and shit.
卖大黄鸟哇
Big yellow bird.
你跟谁较劲儿呢?
Yo, who you bumping with?
没较劲
Ain't no bump.
他们站他们的街角 我站我的
They got their corner, I got mine.
大家太平
Ain't no thing.
你今天去健身房么?
You going up the gym today?
我有空过会儿去找你
I might see you later.
大黄卖哟 卖大黄鸟了喂
Big yellow. Big yellow birds over here.
- 他们可能是跟Marlo的 - 谁都不跟
- Well, maybe they with Marlo. - Ain't with no one.
一帮自己瞎掺和的小兔崽子
They're just young'uns playing in this shit.
你打算怎么办?
So what you want to do?
别在这儿闹事 小心把条子招咱店里来
Don't want to mix here and bring the police to our shop.
等他们撤了 你就跟上
When they step off, you follow.
- 打他个落花流水 - 他们不服怎么办?
- Bank 'em good. - What if they strut?
黄鸟卖了 大黄鸟
Yellow, big yellow.
爆头倒是不必 但要给他们个教训
Ain't no need to pop no one, but they need a warning.
让他们知道我们是来真的
Make sure they know we for real.
断背男卖了 断背男
* Brokeback man Brokeback right here *
新鲜出街的断背男
* Fresh from the street Brokeback *
断背 断背
* Brokeback Brokeback *
大黄鸟
Big yellow bird.
我想找出谁盯着我
Tried to bring out who was on me.
引他去了火车站
Led him to the train station.
然后呢?
How that work?
让铁路警察抓了我
Had the railroad police on me.
烟都不让抽 这家伙有内线
Couldn't smoke. Guy was pulling the strings.
你得找出名字
You need a name.
有了名字 我才能帮你去查
You get that, I can run it down for you.
会有名字的
I'll get a name.
摄像机还在你这儿?
Camera still there?
偷死那狗娘养的
Steal that motherfucker.
如果没人找你问话 那就是FBI的在盯你
No one speaks to it, then it's the feds sniffing you out.
只有联邦警察钱多得流油
It's only federals who'd be rich enough
掉了台摄像机也不至于大哭小叫
to lose a camera and not go to crying about it.
你偷了他 他上门找你
You steal that bitch and someone comes knocking,
那就是地方警察
it's local.
偷死那杂种
Steal that bitch.
然后走着瞧
See what comes.
你认识那个以前跟我一起推车的男孩么
Hey, you know the boy used to be with me running these carts,
叫Sherrod的?
go by the name of Sherrod?
我在找他 我有好消息
I'm looking for him. I've got some good news.
要是你看见他 叫他来找我
So if you spot him, you know, tell him to come see me.
九块两张 十块三张
That's $9 for two, $10 for three.
这也是十块 是好东西哇
That's $10 even too. That's a good product.
不是那种下三赖的垃圾
Ain't none of that alley shit.
走到镜头前招手说哈罗什么的
People walking in front of the camera waving-- waving hello.
那种中国佬做的垃圾
Them Chinese made that shit.
- 嗯 - 不要?
- Yeah. - No?
好兄弟 多谢了
Hey, bro. Much obliged.
好买卖啊 好买卖
It's a good deal, good deal.
嘿 看见我家小子别忘了叫他一声
Hey, remember to holler at my boy if you see him.
好吧
All right.
好吧 走起
All right, here we go!
奶子大全 包君开眼
Bubbles' Depot for my people.
奶子一抖 包君忘忧 包君忘忧哈
Bubbles'll take care of your troubles. Ain't no trouble yet.
好嘛 好嘛 别冲动
All right. All right. Take it easy, okay?
我知道你记得我
I know you remember me.
喂喂 冷静点
All right, be cool with it.
交出来吧 黑鬼--
Give it up, nigga--
这话我以后见你一次说一次
that's what I'm gonna say to you every time we meet.
钱还是药 有啥给啥
Money or pills, don't care which.
好啦 好啦
All right, all right. Cool.
给 我这不拿着么
Cool. I'm getting it.
给
See?
别抢了 人家怪可怜的
Back down, yo. He's in a hole.
小兔崽子 开门撞晦气
Motherfucker bad for business, man.
你们都不管街坊买卖了哇?
Y'all don't take care of your neighborhood store?
怎么了?
What's up?
警官
Officer.
您好哇 警官 能帮帮我吗?
How you doing, Officer? Can you help me out please?
我被抢劫了
I just got robbed.
谢了大哥 他们都看到的
Thank you, man. They all saw it.
这儿每个人都看到了
Everybody was here witnessing everything.
- 抢你钱了? - 对大哥 每天都是这家伙
- Took your money? - Yeah, man. Same guy every day.
他穿过弄堂朝Payson大街去了
you know? He went down the alley towards Payson Street.
你可以从Lafaette街截住他
You can cut him off on Lafayette--
你没许可证不能在街上卖这个
You can't sell on the street without a license.
这些碟子 还是盗版的
And these movies-- it's copyright infringement.
- 帮帮忙啊 兄弟 - 这可是要重罚的
- Come on, man. - That's a hefty fine.
老子的十块啊--
That's my 10--
连你都要抢我?
Are you gonna rob me too?
你也下得了手 你也要抢我?
That's what you're gonna do? You rob me also?
巴尔的摩的公民多有保障啊 谢了您嘞
Baltimore's finest right here. Thank you.
大家都过来一下
Everybody gather up, all right?
大家休息五分钟 都过来下
Everybody take five and gather up.
Mike 你也过来
Mike, get in here too.
我要所有来用健身房的人都听到
I want everybody that uses the gym to hear this now.
你们大都知道我进去很久才出来
Most of y'all know I came home after being in a long time.
你们中的有些人--
And some of y'all--
妈的  所有人大概都知道我同来这里的某位女士
shit, all of y'all probably seen me welcoming the attentions
有比较亲密的往来
of some of the ladies who've come past.
别笑
Easy.
现在
Now,
我知道了其中某些女士是你们的亲戚
I realize that some of these ladies is your relations.
我真不是存心让你们难堪
I ain't mean to disrespect y'all
或者伤害你们感情
or have any feelings hurt.
你们来这儿 全都是为了
All y'all come in here to
学一项运动 做更好的自己
learn a sport and better yourselves.
别让我妨碍了实现这个目的
Ain't no need for me to get in the way of that.
好了
All right.
假如你的目击证人牵扯在内 而Omar揭发了他--
And if your witness is in the game, and Omar jacked him up good--
- 你什么意思你? - 喂 老拐 我只是问问而已
- What the fuck is this? - Hey, Crutch, I'm just asking.
他是你家亲戚啊
Is he kin to you or what?
Vernon 你录了那个老脸皮的口供是吧
Vernon, man, you ran the sheet on that Old Face, right?
对 他人是混蛋 那又怎样?
Yeah. He was an asshole. So what?
什么怎样 这人历史如何
So what? What's the history?
我们有背着你翻你案子的老底么
Do we come behind your casework talking this kind of shit?
- 喂 - 有么?
- Aw. - Do we?
- 好好说 - 好你妈 Bunk
- Come on. - No. Fuck you, Bunk.
- 操你妈 - 操你妈
- Fuck you. - Fuck you.
他一从健身房出来 就给他两下子
Soon as he comes out the gym, yo, bank his ass, man.
好好教训下那黑鬼
Make sure that nigga's shook.
你以为我会置之不理么
You thought I wouldn't handle it.
咱们中的有些人得重新划清地盘
Some of us are in need of some reproof.
这种争来争去的我真不明白
I don't know about all this beefin', man.
怎么 你怕了 黑鬼?
What, you scared, nigga?
看来得给你鼓鼓劲
We need to pump your ass up some more.
行动
Game on.
你丫明天还来不?
You coming round the way tomorrow?
聪明的明天就离那块儿远点
I think you should stay off that spot.
杂种 我跟你说话呢
Bitch, I'm talking to you!
靠 草泥马
Man, fuck you.
干!
Fuck!
识相的就别吃这碗饭 黑鬼
Mouthing don't work for you, nigga.
喂喂喂
Whoa whoa whoa.
你们别在我大门口撒野
Y'all have got to take this shit out of the front of my door.
Namond 进屋去
Namond, go inside.
靠 干你妈!
Man, fuck you!
好了 我知道了 可这没什么好争的
Hey, I feel you, man. Ain't no beef here, though,
行了吧?
all right?
进去 伙计
Go inside, man.
哟 你怎么了
Yo, what happened to your boy?
怎么回事啊
What the fuck happened to you?
没事 你该看看另一个黑鬼什么惨样
Ain't nothing. You need to see how the other nigga look.
- 那谁啊 - 没事
- Who was that? - Ain't nothing.
我能对付得了那白痴 不用你插手
I can handle that fool. You ain't have to step too.
啥呀 对付得了个头 你看看你的脸!
Aw shit, no! You had everything under control. Look at your face!
那个男孩嗑了药才来的
Course, I recognize the other boy was high as all hell.
嗑成那样什么事情都有可能发生
And anything can jump off when it's like that, you know.
要不是你插手他早就屁股开花了
Yeah, and he'd have been on his ass if you ain't mixed in.
怎么回事 他惹什么事了
What's going on? He into something?
不关我的事 也不关你的事
Ain't none of my business. Yours either.
说真的 你们的竞选有声有色啊--
Seriously, you guys ran a hell of a campaign--
毫不松懈 尽心尽力
no let-up, a lot of heart.
- 这点我同意 - 是
- I'll second that. - Yeah.
我尤其喜欢你辩论时 扔出那个目击证人的故事
I liked the shit when you trotted out that witness story during the debate.
那些最后关头放出来的我和黑帮大佬们
What about the fucking last-minute fliers and me and the slum lord
在法院台阶上挑探戈的宣传单怎么说
doing a tango on the courthouse steps?
等等
Wait.
Parker 这事儿到底谁的主意?
Parker, who was behind that?
我可没见Royce的授权书
I didn't see no Royce authority line.
怎么样?
Well?
Tommy 玩笑开够了
Tommy, enough of the bullshit, hmm?
我们还在等什么
What the hell are we waiting for?
屁股挪过来 试试这张宝座
Bring your ass around here and try out the big chair.
来吧 快过来
Come on. Come on around here.
我连候选市长都还不是呢
I'm not even Mayor-Elect.
大选还有好几个星期
General election's still a few weeks away.
要是你在这个我们跟共和党人数
You don't beat Crawford in a city where we outnumber
九比一的城市里还打不过Crawford 你也不配干这行了
Republicans nine to one, you don't deserve the fucking job.
好了 快过来吧
Now, get on around here.
要是大选我输了 我可就怪Norman了
If I lose the general election, I'll just blame Norman here.
是他接替的Terri D'Agostino
He's taking over from Terri D'Agostino.
嗯 她是干得不错
yeah, She did good for you.
的确不错 党中央都注意到了
Yeah, she did. The national noticed.
她回民主党国会竞选委员会去了 专盯着那些红色之州的代表们
She's back at D.C.C.C. Iooking to target red-state delegations.
凭她的成绩 我希望她得到好好的奖励
After what she pulled off, I hope she got a win bonus.
那自然 我的那份他们也给她了
Hell, yeah. They gave her my share too.
你难道不知道么
Wouldn't you know it?
Tommy 你想干什么就去干
Tommy, whatever you need going forward
大选也好 过渡也好--
for the general election, for the transition--
我想立足基层 所以我需要了解各个机构
I want to hit the ground running, so I'm gonna need to learn the agencies,
预算 问题 所有一切
the budgets, the problems-- all of it.
不管你想去哪里 想查什么 尽管放手去干
Wherever you want to go, whatever you want to look at. See to it.
多好一工作啊
It's a hell of a goddamn job.
真高兴退出一半了 我会想念它的
Halfway glad to get out. I'm gonna miss it.
为Braddock那案子在兜圈子
Braddock case running you in circles?
今儿个一天都白跑了
Whole day was a waste of time.
干嘛不和Wardell本人谈谈呢
Why not talk to Wardell himself?
问他是不是他杀了指认他的证人
Ask him if he killed the witness against him.
他要是看报纸 就该知道自己是嫌疑人
If he read the newspapers, he already knows he's a suspect.
看他肯不肯用测谎仪 打电话给他律师
Will he take a polygraph? Call his lawyer.
跟他说毒品的案子就要转交联邦法庭了
Tell him they're about to shift the narcotics case over to the federal court
就因为合法目击证人被谋杀了
because a state witness was murdered.
跟他说要是他的当事人不合作
Tell him if his client doesn't cooperate,
判刑是逃不掉的 还不能假释
he's looking at mandatory minimums and no parole.
联邦法庭才不会接毒品案子呢
The feds don't want drug cases anymore,
尤其是没了关键证人无法进行的案子
especially not a case that's gonna fall apart without a key witness.
吓唬呗 你有啥好怕的
Bluff. What have you got to lose?
也许测出点什么 也许没结果
Maybe he blows the box. Maybe he passes.
可只要他开口 不管说啥
But he talks a bit either way,
你 侦探大人 只管听着
and you, Detective, get to listen.
这看的是啥?
The fuck am l looking at here?
鸟吧 我猜
Birds... I think.
你看那个 我看是拍翅膀呢
You see that there? I think that's a wing flapping.
我操
Shit. Fuck!
干死他老娘
Fuck it anyway, man!
Bond先生?
Mr. Bond?
嗨 叫我Rupert
Hey. Call me Rupert.
谢谢你过来
Thanks for coming over.
我正在准备下一轮选举  跟几个部门头头见下面
Try to get a running start, meeting with my unit chiefs.
没问题
No problem.
这次选举结果出来 恭喜您了
Congratulations on the election result.
你无疑将获得显著的授权
You'll be coming in with quite a mandate.
也许吧
Maybe so.
在过渡期间我有什么能帮忙的吗
So, how can I help you with the transition?
在审当中高端的毒品案子不是很多
There's not a lot of high-end narcotics cases in the pipeline,
- 还有重大刑事案件-- - 出于政治原因这个暂且不谈了
- and major crimes-- - We'll cut it for political reasons.
自从民调结果显示我和Demper势均力敌
Once the polls put me up there with Demper,
就有人在我耳边吹风
people started whispering in my ear.
我也听说你传讯的事情了--
And I also heard about your subpoenas--
Andy Krawczyk  Clay Davis
Andy Krawczyk, Clay Davis.
先生 我不是故意--
Sir, I didn't intend--
在大选前四个星期追着Royce的几个金主?
To go after a couple of Royce's money men four weeks before a primary election?
嗯 我看你干缉毒真是浪费了
Yeah. I think you're wasted in narcotics.
我猜您是想 --
Let me guess--
当V.C.U的行动组负责人怎么样
How about V.C.U. as Unit Chief?
- 啥? - 暴力犯罪小组
- What? - Violent Crimes Unit.
你替我接管那个怎样?
How about you take that over for me?
Carcetti以降低谋杀率为平台
Carcetti ran on a platform of dropping the murder rate,
那V.C.U就是兵家必争之地不是吗
so V.C.U. is where the sparks are gonna fly, right?
您让我负责所有谋杀公诉?
You're putting me in charge of all homicide prosecutions?
那Ilene Nathan呢?
What about llene Nathan?
她升到第二副总了
She's moving up to Second Deputy.
我本来还以为要被踢去轻案组或更糟
I came in here ready to get bounced down to misdemeanors or worse.
你怎么会那么想
Why would you think that?
经过传讯这些事还有Demper--
The subpoenas and the fact that Demper--
Demper毕竟在选举中输了
Demper lost the election.
我赢了
I won.
我羡慕你的勇气 或者不如说忠诚
And I admire your courage, if not your loyalty.
Lester
Lester.
什么?
Excuse me?
请原谅
Forgive me.
V.C.U太好了
V.C.U. is great.
我时刻准备着为您处理谋杀案问题 Bond先生
I'm more than ready to work murders for you, Mr. Bond.
很好
Good.
叫我Rupert
Rupert.
现在她又告诉警察
But now she's told police
说只有跟Paul和Monnel睡是自愿的
sex was consentual on Paul and Monnel only. So...
- 那Randy-- - 他明天回来
- So, Randy-- - He'll be back tomorrow.
- 那警察那边呢? - 这我可管不着
- And the thing with the police? - It's out of my hands.
安静点 姑娘们
Turn it down, ladies.
Quanice 口香糖吐了
Quanice, lose the gum.
好了 都坐好
Okay. Settle down.
Prezbo老师! 计算机是干嘛的
Mr. Prezbo! What's he doing with a computer?
我们有些特殊课题会用到计算机
We're gonna have a computer in the class for special projects,
- 另外 - 靠 他妈够新的哇
- and another thing-- - Dang! They all new and shit.
旧版就留在桌子上
Leave the old ones on your desks,
在新版内页的框里写上你们的名字
and put your names on the box on the inside cover of the new ones.
好吧 大家做回家作业都有困难吗
Okay. Did anyone have any trouble with the homework?
- Charlene? - 我做不来
- Charlene? - I didn't get it.
- 什么做不来 - 一点都做不来
- Didn't get what? - None of it.
Michael?
很好 做得好
That's great. Good job.
搞毛啊
Come on, eh?
Calvin 这是你做的吗 看上去像别人做的
Calvin, is this your work? 'Cause it looks like someone else's.
没 我自己做的
No, I did my work.
好吧 下次记得别把Quanice的名字也抄上去
Okay. Next time, try to remember not to copy Quanice's name at the top.
好 大家都拿到新书了么?
All right. Did everybody get a new textbook?
嗯
Yes.
很好 好
Great. Okay.
大家可以暂时把书放一边了
Well, for now at least, you can get those out of sight.
好哇
- Whoa! - That's right!
Namond 你怎么没穿校服
Namond, why aren't you in uniform?
为什么决定不穿呢
Why did you decide not to wear it?
又不是在自己班里 穿什么校服啊
I ain't in my right class, so ain't no need for a uniform.
有意思
Interesting.
你干嘛把我们写的每句话都记下来
Why you always write down everything we say?
想猜我们的想法还怎么的
Trying to get inside our heads or something?
你现在是想猜我的想法么
You trying to get into mine?
Chandra 你以为这里是美容院还是教室啊
Chandra, do you think this is a beauty salon or a classroom?
Darnell 你又为什么不穿校服呢?
Darnell, why didn't you wear your uniform?
我也想的 真的
I meant to. I did.
是啊 但一夸脱伏特加下去
Yeah, but after a quart of vodka,
谁还记得清该穿什么颜色的衣服啊
it'd be hard to know what color shirt you're supposed to be wearing.
你觉得这很好笑么 Namond?
And you find that funny, Namond?
靠 操你
Man, fuck you.
Darnell有酗酒问题 Namond嘛我们觉得
Darnell has a drinking problem, and Namond, we believe,
- 有挑衅性品行障碍 - 我操
- suffers from conduct-disorder issues. - Fuck you.
他那张嘴是够呛
Yeah, he's got a mouth on him.
Chandra 你真有必要在教室里梳头么
Chandra, is it necessary to comb your hair in class?
去死 丑脸的婊子
Fuck you, cheese-faced bitch!
- 我只不过想跟你说... - 放你他娘的狗屁
- I should tell you-- - You ain't tellin' nobody nothing!
嗯 我还在想她怎么回来的呢 看着挺...
Yeah. You know, I was wondering why she was in the class. She seemed so--
- Chandra 听我说 - 对立挑衅性人格
- Chandra, listen to me. - Oppositional defiant personality.
你他妈给我滚 婊子
Get the fuck out of my face, bitch!
我很遗憾你今天心情不好
I'm sorry you're having a bad day,
但是请你跟Mason小姐出去走一圈
but you're gonna have to take a little walk with Miss Mason.
等你冷静下来了再回来
Come back when you've pulled it all back together again.
靠 咱丫头Chandra玩完喽
Damn. It's bye-bye time for my girl Chandra.
哦 是么?
Yeah, you think?
重申一下 这是一次测谎试验
Then to reiterate, this is a polygraph examination--
非法定程序 所有问题的答案
non-admissible, and the answers to all questions are regarded
作为辅助证据 仅有有限的参考价值
as a proffer with a limited grant of immunity.
- 同意 - 好
- Agreed. - Okay.
首先 请对以下所有问题回答"是"
To begin, please answer yes to a series of questions
无论实际答案是否正确
regardless of whether or not that answer is correct.
- 你的姓名是Anthony Wardell么? - 对
- Is your name Anthony Wardell? - Yeah.
你来自马里兰州的巴尔的摩么?
And you're from Baltimore, Maryland?
我现在关在市立监狱 但我的确是东区人
Right now I'm over at City Jail, but I'm from East Side.
所以你的答案是?
So your answer is?
对 我是巴尔的摩人
Yeah, I'm from Baltimore.
你是女性么?
Are you female?
你他妈脑子有病 -- 抱歉
Fuck is wrong with-- my bad.
对 我是个婊子
Yeah, I'm a bitch.
- 嘿 小妞儿 - Chandra
- Hey, sweet thing. - Chandra.
我们在写小论文
We're working on our short essay.
- 请你 - 钻石是女人最好的朋友
- If you-- - Diamonds are a girl's best friend.
想要发财 先得剥光
Need to get down to lay down.
Namond 如果你不住嘴 我就要把你请出去了
Namond, if you don't stop, I'm gonna have to ask you to leave class.
你们这帮倒霉蛋 三天以后见啦
See you sad-ass motherfuckers in about three days--
请出教室 不能离校
You're leaving class, not school.
啥?
What?
这样怎么着 婊子 啊 啊
What about now, bitch? Huh? Huh?
这样毫无必要 Namond
That's not necessary, Namond.
哦 你要让我停学?
Oh, you gonna suspend me?
我们需要谈一下
We're gonna have a little talk.
靠 去死吧 我知道你们的规矩
Man, fuck y'all. I know the rules.
你一定得停我学 学校有规定的
You've got to suspend me. School's got to have rules.
他说得对 总该有规矩的
He's right. You've got to have rules.
不能就这么把他扔出去了
Can't just be throwing that shit out.
关键在于 你让我说什么我就能说什么
The point is: I can call it like you want.
你说他过了吧 他就过了
You want him to pass? He passed.
你让我说他结果可疑吧 那就可疑
You want him to come up inconclusive, he's inconclusive.
这他妈算什么科学啊
What the fuck kind of science is that?
他到底是测出来说谎了没有啊
Come on. Did he blow the box or not?
我听您的 探员
I'm here for you, Detective.
你知道我们为何要做测谎 搞点筹码啊
You know what we use the polygraph for? Leverage.
把他弄进来好好搞搞脑子
To get him in here and fuck with him.
难怪这没有法律效力呢
No wonder this shit's inadmissible.
叫我看
Let me guess.
他们站外面 Swatowski告诉他们
They're out in the hall and Swatowski is telling them
他可以按照他们的想法出结果
that he can make it go any way they want.
要是你觉得我们在耍手段 干嘛还让你的客户--
If you think that's how we play it, then why let your client--
因为你们知道已经没什么官司好打了
Because you know there's not much case left
你的目击证人都死了
now that your witness is dead.
如果我能避免 当然不会让他去上联邦法庭
I don't need to expose him to a federal charge if I can avoid it.
何况就算Swatowski听你们的
And because even if Swatowski bends it for our ears,
这也是他在暗示Wardell先生没有说谎
he's let you know that Mr. Wardell here did not blow the box.
换做是我 就不会想置我于死地
Yo, I wouldn't kill me.
就算测出我说谎 人也不是我杀的
Even if it flips on me, I ain't gonna do shit to the man.
怎讲?
Why not?
我妈跟他妈 跟表姐妹似的
My moms and his-- they're, like, cousins.
当初一块儿上Latrobe来
Came up together in the Latrobe, you know?
我跟他 那是打从娘胎就认识哇
I've been knowing him since, like, Head Start and shit.
可他本要指认你
But he was gonna testify.
凭那案子 就算我认了罪又能判多久
What am I looking at on the first conviction on this kind of waive?
七年 八年 操 最多三年半就能出去了
Seven, eight? Shit, I'll be out in three and a half.
你觉得我为了三年半 就要杀我娘小姐妹的儿子?
You think I'm gonna kill my mom's cousin's boy for three and a half?
我知道他毛遂自荐
I know that man helped get himself elected
要指认我干了这些那些的
claiming that I did me like that, but please.
可他不出来 别的混蛋也要指认我
Bum-ass motherfucker was gonna testify against me,
我向老天发誓他死了我很难过
and I swear to God I feel bad he's dead.
真的
I do.
嘿 llene
Hey, llene
我到处找你呢
I've been looking all over for you.
Omar Little
Omar Little.
几年前Bird那案子给的
From Bird's trial a couple of years ago.
- 那个抢劫的小子 - 嗯
- The stickup boy. - Mm-hmm.
他因为一起重大杀人案被关在市立监狱里
He's in City Jail on a felony murder.
商店抢劫 西区的
Store robbery, West Side.
我给他这张卡片 最多是免个小偷小摸的
When I gave him the card, I told him it was for a light felony at best.
是 话是没错
Yeah, of course,
可他得拿到张调令调出市拘留所
but he needs to get writ out of B.C.D.C.
放到哪里保护性拘留起来
and put in protective custody somewhere else.
他现在呆的地方有八百壮汉对他虎视眈眈
He's sharing his address with about 800 other guys
个个都巴不得他早点横死枪口
who have seen the business end of his shotgun.
关你什么事?
Why do you care?
我相信他是被人算计了
I'm pretty sure he's being set up.
真的 刑侦队里其他人也这么认为?
Really? How does that play with the rest of the guys in the squad room?
我只求你把他送到什么县级拘留所
Look, all I'm asking is that you move him to some county detention center
至少等到我想办法回案子上来了再说
at least until I have a chance to work back up on this thing.
这张名片这点人情总够用吧
Now, this card ought to buy him that much.
Hartford县拘留所够安静了吧?
Is Hartford County Detention Center quiet enough?
- 行 - 去我办公室拿张调令吧
- Yeah. - Go pick up a writ in my office
告诉Little先生我不欠他什么了
and tell Mr. Little my debt's paid.
事实证明 今年西区的凶杀案
The fact is that homicides are off
降低了14个百分点
14% in the West Side this year.
但我不会站在这儿沾沾自喜
But I'm not gonna stand here and take credit for that
尤其是其他犯罪统一报告都在上升
when all other U.C.R. felonies are up.
何出此言呢 警司长?
Why not, Major?
我连警司都不是的时候 曾经有位智者告诉过我
A wise man once told me years ago when I wasn't even a sergeant
当犯罪率下降的时候你决不可居功
that you should never take credit when the crime rate drops
除非你打算在犯罪率上升的时候吃瘪
unless you want to take the blame when it rises.
立正 未来市长驾到
Atten-hut. Mayor-Elect is on deck.
请大家该干嘛干嘛 我只是作为议员来视察
Please, back to what you're doing. I'm just a councilman here to observe.
稍息 各位
At ease, gentlemen.
Daniels警司长 请继续发言
Major Daniels, continue your presentation.
一般而言我都让一辆两人警车在 贩毒最厉害的几个街角蹲点
In any event, rather than allow my post cars to patrol,
而不是让他们开着满大街巡逻
I put two-man cars in the post with the worst drug corners:
Edmonson大道 Poplar路
Edmonson Avenue, Poplar Grove,
Fayette和Baltimore大街
Fayette and Baltimore Streets,
北方大道
North Avenue.
不说其他 两人警车具有足够的威胁性
Now, if nothing else, a two-man car is more aggressive,
可将交易赶出这些最为活跃的场所
and that helps push it away from the most volatile corners,
- 可能就是这点起了作用 - 赶出就行了?
- which may be having an effect. - Just pushing it?
我不会浪费警力在追捕廉价的街头犯罪上 总督
I'm not devoting my resources to cheap street arrests, Commissioner.
相反 我正想办法集中警力
Instead, I'm trying to bring every officer I can
来对付重大刑事案件
to bear on making quality felony cases.
我本可以做更多 但是以我之见
I could do more but, well, it's my opinion
我手下的部队中 缺乏训练有素的警员
that not enough of the troops I have are sufficiently trained
来有效调查此类案件
to properly investigate such cases.
警司长 你这是在侮辱你的长官
Major, you just insulted your command.
无意冒犯 长官 我手下太多人长年累月
Respectfully, sir, too many of my people have spent years
在街上抓小混混 扑倒扭打这个他们在行
chasing street-level arrests while they grab bodies and make stats.
但这并不代表他们会写合格的逮捕令
But that doesn't teach you how to write a proper warrant
或者对事因做出合理的举证
or testify properly as to probable cause
或者如何利用线人而不是被线人利用
or use, and not get used by an informant.
我真心希望事不至此
I wish it were otherwise.
但如果要追查重罪
But if I'm chasing felony cases,
我手下只有少数警官能够胜任
I can only bring a minority of my officers to bear.
- 都已经给你了啊! - 鬼信你
- You've got all of it already! - That's right.
非找抽是吧 你丫欠扁是吧
Make a nigga work. You like that shit.
是吧啊 老不要脸的?
Ain't that right, motherfucker?
你躲不了 小子
You can't hide, son.
不管你藏在哪儿
Don't care where it is.
你躲一黑鬼的屁眼里我照样能找到你
In a nigga's ass crack, I'll still find you.
靠 那老不死的
Damn. Fucked that man up.
- 是啊 - 好了
- Yeah, boy. - All right.
我们今天开始得有点晚
So we starting a little later than I wanted.
喂 是你自己说午饭后从学校溜出来的
Yo, but you said you was gonna creep out of school after lunch.
我试了 他们不让我走
I tried. They won't put me out.
靠 要是爷想走 没哪个学校关得住我
Shit. Ain't no school gonna hold me if I want to go.
是他们让我进的这个新班级
It's this new class they put me in.
他妈傻逼透了 教的东西简直是倒退
It's so fucked up, yo, they working all backwards and shit.
好了 快干活吧
All right, let's get to this:
你 Bobby 你负责拿货
Yo, Bobby, you working the stash.
喂喂 干嘛不在昨天那地方卖  那儿市口好啊
Yo yo, why aren't where we was yesterday? The spot was right.
这里不好吗?
this is good here?
你有病啊 他昨天卖疯了
What the fuck is wrong with you? He was on this strip yesterday.
这里算个毛
This ain't shit.
你要是不想卖 就给我滚 Kenard
Yo, if you don't want to sell my shit, then fuck you, Kenard.
钱我自己拿
I keep my money.
这地方没啥不好的
This spot is just as good as the other.
靠...
Shit...
Carv 你知道这摄像机多少钱么?
Carv, do you know how much that video camera costs?
$4200 跟这比起来 Fuzzy Dunlop那次历险
$4,200, which makes our adventure with Fuzzy Dunlop
就像他妈的公园散步似的
Iook like a fucking walk in the park.
从监察局拿出那台摄像机
To get the camera from l.S.D.,
我不也要有你上级的授权才行么?
I had to get authorization from your supervisor, right?
是 可你怎么也是干公事的时候掉的 你们队长会理解的
Still, you lost it doing police work. Your lieutenant will understand.
Marimow? 那个傻逼理解个屁
Marimow? You know what that asshole understands?
为这点小事就能把我生吞活剥了
Burning motherfuckers for petty shit like this.
- 帮帮我吧 Carv - 这不关我的事
- Help me, Carv. - This is not my problem.
别忽悠我哈 Carv 你可别忽悠我
Don't fuck me, Carv. Don't fuck me now.
你知道这怎么回事么?
You know what this is?
这就是人说的纵容关系
This is one of those enabling relationships.
那就纵容我呗 Carv
Enable me, Carv.
纵容我找到该死的相机为止
Enable me to find my fuckin' camera.
你说看到了鸽子?
You're seeing pigeons?
昨晚是看见了
Last night we did.
我和Sydnor跑遍西区把每个鸽子窝都找遍了
Me and Sydnor ran the Westside Iooking at every pigeon coop we could find.
今天早上 监视器上就什么都没了
This morning, nothing in the monitor.
- 你们查了当铺没? - 每家都查了
- Did you check the pawnshops? - Every one.
我就他妈知道是Marlo这混蛋拿的
I fucking know this asshole Marlo has my camera.
- 啊 我靠 - 咋了?
- Aw, fuck me. - What?
你一说倒提醒我了
You just reminded me.
我本要去听一孩子汇报说他知道
I had to brief this kid last week who said he knew
Marlo的人干的什么谋杀的事
something about a murder that Marlo's people did.
- 本想让Bunk去问的 - Bunk在管这案子?
- I meant to call Bunk on it. - Bunk caught the case?
不 他本来要追捕的人被弄死了
No. Actually, he had a warrant for the guy who supposedly got killed.
以前我跟他一起处理过那案子
I rode around with him on it a while back.
那我怎么办?
What about me?
兄弟我有难啊 伙计
I got problems here, man.
你能做的就是抓住Marlo Stanfield 和他手下人的把柄
The only thing you can do is get some wood on Marlo Stanfield or his people.
吓唬他把摄像机还回来
Scare him enough to send the camera back.
你有他什么证据么?
What do you have on Marlo?
我知道他贩毒 但是没证据 我就是知道
I know he's a drug dealer. I can't prove it or nothing, but I know.
好吧 听着
Okay, listen.
要不我让你先审这娃子?
How about I let you debrief the kid first?
- 看他能给你什么消息 - 这能把摄像机弄回来么?
- See what he can give you. - This gets the camera home?
也许不能 但你跟着小混混聊聊 说不定他能抖出些Marlo的料来
Maybe not, but you talk to the runt, and maybe he gives you some shit on Marlo.
说不定还能挖出件谋杀案 你打电话给凶杀组前
Maybe even gives you a murder or two. Before you call Homicide on it,
捏着这事儿去找Marlo 岂不就像猫咬着老鼠一样么
you walk it back to Marimow Iike the cat with the mouse in its teeth.
你用谋杀吓他 说不定他就不在乎摄像机了
You bring him the murder, he probably forgives the camera.
Lumen 5号线
Lumen, line 5.
Lumen 快他妈的接电话
Lumen, pick up the fucking phone.
我找Moreland警官
Looking for Detective Moreland.
你能请他打回给西区的Carver警长么?
Could you have him call Sergeant Carver at the Western, please?
Carver? 西区的?
Carver? Western?
嗯 明白了
Hmm. Got it.
去死吧 Bunk
Fuck that Bunk.
- 关于内阁你有什么想法 - 好多呢
- Thoughts on your cabinet? - Lots of them.
不过首当其冲的是  Ervin Burrell一定要给我滚
But top of the list, Ervin Burrell's ass is gone.
一年多前我就让Royce弄掉他
I told Royce to dump him more than a year ago,
但Clarence不想在大选之前得罪各位部长
but Clarence didn't want to piss off the ministers until after the primary.
大选结束了 他可以下手了哇
Primary's over. He can do it now.
你以为Clarence Royce会替你挨枪子?
You think Clarence Royce is gonna do you that favor?
他已经打着算盘要绊倒Elijah
He's already thinking about taking a poke at Elijah
争夺第七选取的国会议员席位呢
and running for the Seventh District congressional seat.
他巴不得拉拢全市每个黑人部长
He's gonna need every black minister in town to lay hands upon him.
- 好吧 那我亲自下手 - 不 想都别想
- Fine. I'll do it myself. - No, you won't.
Royce可以炒黑人警督的鱿鱼
Royce can fire a black police commissioner,
新当选的白人市长就不行
but the newly-elected white mayor cannot.
你的支持者 水能载舟亦能覆舟
Same brothers who voted for you'll be at your throat.
要是我另找个黑人指挥官 来替代这狗娘养的呢
What if I got a black commissioner to replace the son of a bitch?
Burrell手下唯一的黑人副手就是Cawthorne
Under Burrell, the only black deputy is Cawthorne,
他都70岁了
and he's 70.
剩下的不是警司长就是队长了
After that, it's just majors and lieutenants.
我们出去找 全国撒网
We go outside-- nationwide search.
纽约和洛城的副处长挣得比警察局总督都多
Deputy chiefs in New York or L.A. make more than their police commissioner.
如果有才又是黑人 干嘛还留在巴蒂尔摩?
If you're talented and black, why would you be in Baltimore?
这个问题我在不同场合下
I have often asked myself that very question
问过自己无数遍了
on a number of occasions.
这么说我甩不掉Burrell了 操
So I'm stuck with Burrell. Fuck.
坐
Have a seat.
别弄太晚 他明早还要上学呢
Don't keep him late. He's got to be at school in the morning.
你不是说他被停学了么
I thought you said he was suspended.
他们让我明天回去上课 Anna小姐让我九点前回家
They're letting me back in tomorrow. Miss Anna'd want me to be home by 9:00.
别忘了问完话把他送去Bunk那儿
Don't forget to send him on to Bunk after you're done.
好好照顾他 多好一孩子呀
Look after him. He's a good kid.
你饿不饿?
You hungry?
- 嗯 - 吃饭去呗
- Yeah. - Let's eat.
小子 问你个问题不进记录的
Hey, kid, let me ask you right off the bat
你知道警用监控录像机长啥样儿吧?
You know what a police surveillance camera looks like?
议员先生 您确定不和Grace队长同坐?
Councilman, you sure you don't want to ride with Lieutenant Grace?
她是本次行动的总指挥啊
I mean, she'll be in command of the ship.
微服私访跟着头儿还有什么意思?
What's the point of a ride-along with the bosses?
我该见大伙儿之所见嘛
I need to see what the troops see, right?
好 我很期待有个知己知彼的市长
Fine. I love the idea of a mayor who knows what we're up against.
McFarley和Ginter警官
Officers McFarley and Ginter,
这位是候选市长 他跟你们一辆车巡视第三区
this is the mayor-elect, and he'll be riding with you in sector three.
- 你好 - 好
- How you doing? - Hey.
别让他被抓了
Don't let him get captured.
当然一开始我什么都不知道
Obviously, I didn't know nothing about it in the beginning.
小Kevin 他让我告诉Lex
Little Kevin-- he just told me to tell Lex
到Fulton后的操场去等着
to go up to the playground behind Fulton
说是他的妞在那儿
'cause his girl was up there.
- 后来Lex就被杀了? - 对
- And Lex got killed? - Yeah.
在哪儿被杀的
Where'd he get killed?
这么说他被杀的时候你不在现场
So you actually weren't there to see him killed?
我跟你说了 小Kevin他只叫我
I told you. Little Kevin, he just told me
告诉Lex去操场见他的妞Patrice
to tell Lex to go up to the playground and see this girl Patrice.
再后来 Kevin过来告诉我
Then later, Kevin come up to me and tell me
Chris和Snoop把那家伙做掉了
Chris and Snoop killed the dude.
- Kevin他姓什么? - 我不知道
- What's Kevin's last name? - I don't know.
- 你连他姓什么都不知道? - 我只知道他叫小Kevin
- You don't have his name? - Little Kevin is all I know.
我这么说遍你听着 你让这家伙去一个地方
So let me get this straight: You told the guy to go somewhere,
然后就听说他被杀了  可你不知道他在哪儿被杀的
and then you heard he was killed, but you don't know where he was killed,
你也不知道有没有人发现过尸体
and you don't even know if anyone ever found the body?
- 你怎么知道Lex真死了 - 人人都知道哇
- How do you know Lex is really dead? - Everybody know it.
- 人人是谁? - 道上所有兄弟啊
- Who is everybody? - Everybody from around the way.
听着 大家都在说
Yo, listen. People be saying
Chris和Snoop在帮Marlo把黑鬼变成僵尸
that Chris and Snoop be turning niggas into zombies for Marlo,
可我知道这不是真的
but I know that ain't true.
你一旦死 就死翘翘了
When you dead, you dead is all.
僵尸啊
Zombies, huh?
你知道怎么回事儿不 鬼扯
You know what this is? This is bullshit.
- 你在跟我鬼扯蛋 - 没有 先生
- You're bullshitting me. - No, sir.
那个叫Lex翘辫子的时候你就在现场 对不对
You were right there when this Lex fellow got dropped, weren't you?
- 不在 - 你就在
- No. - Yes, you were.
你就是能让我抓到Snoop和Chris的目击证人
You're an eyeball witness who can get me Snoop and Chris both.
- 我说了 - 听着小子 你要是在那儿就说出来
I told you-- Look, kid. If you were there, you can say so.
我们会尽力帮你
We can do a lot for you,
你学校的麻烦说不定也能帮你解决
maybe help you out with this problem you got at the school.
我已经没有麻烦了 都弄清了
I ain't got a problem no more. I'm good with that.
- 得了吧 你就在那儿的好不好? - Herc
- come on, You were there, right? - Herc.
说你在现场的!
Just say you were there!
你当市长有啥感想啊
So how do you like being mayor so far?
大选还没赢呢 就算就职典礼也要到12月呢
I've still got to win the general election and the inauguration's not till December.
- 我能有什么感想? - 你总不见得干得比Royce还差
- So what do I know? - Well, you can't do any worse than Royce.
市里被他弄得屎一样
City's going to shit.
这个嘛
Yeah. Well,
你们建议我先做什么
what do you guys suggest I do first?
空袭呗 用白磷弹啊
- An air strike. White phosphorus. - yeah
从这儿到北大街全都撒一遍
Drop that shit on everything between here and North Avenue.
真的 倍儿管用
Seriously. That shit works.
我哥是海军陆战队的
My brother's a marine, right?
他们在以色列费卢杰就用白磷弹
They use W.P. over there in Fallujah.
13号警报 发生枪击 北Calhoun街200号
Signal 13, shots fired. 200 North Calhoun.
砰 说来就来
Bang. There it is.
准备好见识见识狗屁吧市长先生  抱歉我说脏话了
Now you're gonna see some shit, Mr. Mayor. Pardon my French.
你知道什么最扯么
You know what's fucked up?
没人听见开枪
No one hears the gunshot.
周边协查的人野都没说听到枪响
On the canvas, no one even claims to hear the shot.
这么着 我们再重头研究Wardell的访问名单
So look, our next move is to work back o Wardell's visiting list.
警长问起来就说我出街了
If the sergeant asks, I'm on the street.
靠 Calhoun街上有枪击案?
Fuck, is that 13 on Calhoun Street?
不知道 不过十分钟前就有人出警了
I don't know, but they 1032'd 10 minutes ago, sir.
你们该不会把我送到家门口吧
You're not dropping me off at my crib, are you?
你们可以把我送到离家一两条街外
I mean, you can leave me, like, a block or two up from here.
剩下的我自己走回去就好了
I could walk the rest of the way.
不想被人见到跟警察在一块儿?
Don't want to be seen with the police, huh?
嗯
Yeah.
行 老板 就在这儿把你放下吧
All right, boss. I'll pull over right here.
Carv在想些什么  这孩子根本就不知道什么谋杀
What the fuck was Carv thinking? This kid can't give me a murder.
咱直接去找Marlo
We go right at Marlo.
能正大光明干嘛还要走后门
Fuck the backdoor when we can go in the front, you know?
请派一名探员在大学驻守
Next I want a detective at University in case the guy
免得有人胡乱发表什么言论
that comes out makes any kind of declaration.
对 叫人在房间看着他
Right, and have someone in the room with him.
Leach警官在一名警长的陪同下正前往你处
Officer Leach is being transported down to you by a sergeant.
由Hollister探长带领的武警 在去往Ballistics的路上
Service weapon's with Detective Hollister, on their way to Ballistics.
不不 看上去像是一枪毙命
No. No, looks like a clean shoot.
现场有疑似两种不同枪支留下的弹壳 口径不同 都是遗失枪支
I've got spent shells from two suspect weapons, different calibers, both recovered.
嗯嗯 我明白了
Right. Yeah, I know.
不 我不是负责现场的
No, I'm not out here at the scene.
不过打个电话给P.I.O.让他从市里带份申明过来
But call the P.I.O. and have him issue a statement from downtown.
告诉S.A.O.要是他们想派人来勘察现场
Tell the S.A.O. that if they want to have someone out here survey the scene,
动作要快了 犯罪实验室快完工了
they need to move now 'cause Crime Lab is finishing up,
O.C.M.E.的卡车也在这儿等着了
and the O.C.M.E. van is here waiting.
这不是西区警局总指挥嘛
isn't that the Western District commander?
对 Daniels
Yeah, that's Daniels.
他是今晚值班领导
He's the duty officer tonight.
他好像挺内行的啊
Seems to know his business.
跟有些人比起来好多了
He ain't as bad as some.
警察
Police.
巴尔的摩警察
Baltimore Police.
九月份有85人有资格参加
Okay. There's still 85 eligible from September
排到十月分
who need an October day.
那也行啊 太太
That'll work, ma'am.
就靠你俩在月底前完成了
I'm counting on you fellows to get it done before the end of the month.
我工资就付到你们那个时候吧
I can keep you on salary till then.
怎么说呢 这不适合我
You know what? This ain't for me.
感谢您给我机会 女士
Look. I thank you for the opportunity, ma'am,
但就请个人来个一两天没什么大用处
but it ain't so much just to bring a man for a day or two.
我是说
I mean,
要是能有个我能正经教孩子们的地方...
if you had something where I was working with these kids...
算了 多谢了
Anyway, thanks again.
- David - 嗨
- David. - Hey.
还以为你在lda Wells呢
Thought you was at lda Wells.
这里开了言语艺术课 我去年就来了
Language arts position opened up here, so I came over last year.
- 教练好 - 好
- Hey. What's up, Coach? - Hey.
你为了孩子们来的 有什么项目?
You come over for some of your boys today? Some kind of program?
不不 别的事儿 反正也没戏
Nah. Something else. Didn't work out really.
保重
Be well.
你介意我和他谈谈么
You mind if I give him a go?
- 行啊 - 操你妈
- Sure. - Fuck you!
好吧
Okay.
不过你别想离开这房间
But you're still in this room.
操你妈!
Fuck you!
你端正行为前是不能回到教室去的
You know you're not going back with the others till you learn to behave.
- 操你妈 - 除非你能学会自控
- Fuck you. - Until you show you can handle it,
否则不可能回到原来的班级上
you're not going back to your regular class.
操你妈
Fuck you.
你也别梦想着回家了  因为不会给你停学的
Look. And you damn sure ain't going home 'cause there ain't no more getting suspended.
Colvin先生
Mr. Colvin, sir?
操你妈
Fuck you.
我不想写 就那么回事儿 放屁
'Cause I ain't feel like it. That's why. This is bullshit.
我才不要读什么狗屁教科书呢
And I ain't reading no motherfucking book either!
他妈都不知道讲些什么
I don't even know nothing about the damn book.
老是拿书什么的来烦我
And you always getting on my ass and shit about some book.
去死吧 你个贱婊子
Fuck you, you cheese-faced bitch!
Albert Albert 冷静点
Albert, Albert, settle down now.
这比我们预计的要困难许多
This gonna be harder than we thought, man.
- 很有趣嘛 不是吗? - 好了 同学们...
- It's fascinating, isn't it? - All right. Class...
这跟其他班级一点区别都没有
This ain't no different than the other class...
临床上看
Clinically speaking.
喂 你全押上了
Yo, your point's full.
手气旺呗 有种就跟啊
I'm hot. Come and get it.
好哇 跟就跟
All right. I'll cover that.
- 我也跟 - 我押咱家Randy的
- Me too. - I'm betting with my boy Randy.
准备着乖乖送钱吧
You about to get your money taken.
哇靠
Come on.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thank you. - Thank you.
付钱啊 没种的
Pay up, sucker.
Randy 你干嘛呢 我们不是讲过了嘛
Randy, what are you doing? Didn't we go over this?
有多少种可能扔出个四来?
How many ways can you make a four?
不够他小黑腚子耍的
Not enough for his black ass.
看谁说的
Look who's talking.
他今天才来 你讲的概率他都没听到
Yo, he just come today, so he missed the whole thing about the odds.
好吧
Right.
Randy
Randy,
扔出个四 只有三种可能 但扔出七
there's only three ways to make a four, but to make a seven
- 六种 - 很好
- Six. - That's good.
所以你该怎么玩儿
So what should have been your play?
应该赌他不赢
Should have bet against her roll.
明白就好啊 Wagstaff先生
Good to have you back, Mr. Wagstaff.
来吧 转起来
Come on, roll 'em, man.
我押40 我也押40
I got 40. I got 40 on it.
让他们以为没在学习 其实学进去了
Trick them into thinking they aren't learning, and they do.
我到处找你
Been looking all over for you.
你不找到了
You found me.
我一直在想 Sherrod...
Look, I been thinking, Sherrod...
咱俩关系一直处理得不好
we're going about our thing all wrong.
那啥 是我的错
You know, look, I made the mistake.
总以为我比你了解你自己
I was thinking I knew you better than you knew yourself.
这街角的买卖会很快毁了你的
This corner-- this corner mess will bring you down fast.
真的 还是快回来吧啊?
You know. I think you need to come home, right?
你今晚回来 咱一起想办法好不好
You come by tonight, and we work this shit out together? why?
我一直在想 你现在就跟我回去吧
I been thinking about it. Why don't you just step right now?
我八点才领工钱
I don't get paid till 8:00.
八点呀
8:00, huh?
你没事吧
You all right?
就是有点累 没事
Just a little tired, that's all.
那今晚见好吧 Sherrod?
So I'm gonna see you tonight, right, Sherrod?
你来不来帮我录口供?
You want to help me take his statement?
Braddock的案子破了
Braddock case is down.
二号房
Room two.
你们这些老当兵的管这叫什么?
You veteran crimefighters got a name for this here, right?
"凶器"还是其他什么的?
"Murder weapon" or some shit like that?
不可能吧
No fucking way.
尸检发现两处吻合
Slug from autopsy matches two more
我从猎狗的后院刨出来的
I pulled from that smoke hound's backyard,
埋在Braddock送命的小巷子里
block into the side alley from where Braddock fell.
死的不巧 枪走火
Our guy's dead from a stray.
他在练习远距离打箱子瓶子
He was shooting at 40s and Clorox bottles blocks away,
用土豆当消声器
using potatoes for a silencer.
哇靠 太扯了
Bite me. That's ridiculous.
咱家伙死了就因为他没打中洗洁精瓶子?
So our guy's dead because a bullet misses a bleach bottle.
那Carcetti就因为这二逼事儿当上市长
And this fuck Carcetti gets to be the mayor behind this stupidity.
我真他妈爱这城市
I fucking love this town.
真心的
I do.
好样的 兄弟
Nice pull, Greggs.
没见过啊
What's up, guys?
Sherrod
Sherrod!